hey guys we have a calculus problem here
the integral of x^2 Ln X DX we're going
to solve this using integration by parts
so it's saying the integral of U DV is
equal to UV minus the integral of V duu
so we need to find u duu v and DV this
stuff on the left side of the equal sign
is our original integral so we need to
find a u and a DV somewhere inside here
so for the U we're going to do lnx and
for the DV we're going to do x^2 DX
and now we've built out our left hand
side this integral of UV is the integral
x^2 Ln X DX and then to fill out the
rest of this we need to find V and du so
du is the derivative of U and the
derivative of Ln of X is 1x DX and then
to find V we need to take the
anti-derivative that's going to be power
rule so we're going to add one to the
two and then divide by that number so 2
+ 1 is 3 and then we're going to divide
by three and now we have everything we
need to go to our next step to fill this
out so the U is going to be lnx V is
going to be X Cub over 3 now let's
change the order and then we're going to
subtract the integral of V which is X
Cub over 3 * du which is 1x DX and then
we can clean things up a little bit all
of this can be put over three and then
we can subtract the integral where we
have X Cub overx which is x^2 and this
1/3 can be brought in front and we still
have the DX and now for the next step
there's nothing we can really do here
and same thing we can bring down the
constant multiple and then we're going
to take the integral ultimately we added
one to the two and then divided by that
and then we don't want to forget the
plus C in the denominator this 3 * 3 can
become nine and we can put a box around
it this is a great answer but let's say
it's a multiple choice test and this was
not one of the answers we can simplify
this a little bit further to match what
might be on a multiple choice test we
can give this the same denominator as
this so we'll multiply top and bottom by
three this 3 * 3 will give us 9 and this
three can be brought over and now we can
pull out a GCF both of these have an X
cubed in the numerator and a 9 in the
denominator so after we Factor those
things out we're left with a 3 Ln X and
then after we factored out of this other
term we just have a one and then we
don't want to forget the plus C and
here's another valid way to answer it
and this is a classic example for
integration by parts how exciting